Hello everyone and welcome
to EnglishPod, my name is Marco.
My name is Catherine and today we've got
an intermediate level lesson for you guys.
Now Marco what are we talking about today?
That's right, today we're
going to try to buy a new car.
So we're going to the car dealer and we
want to try and see if we can get a new car.
Okay, so lots of great
vocabulary for buying that car.
Let's check out today's dialogue.
We'll be back in a moment.
Hi there, I am looking for a new car.
I have this old Ford Pinto
that I would like to trade in.
I see.
You are in look this month because
all of our 2010 models are on sale.
It is a perfect time to buy a new
car since it's the end of the year.
Perfect.
I like this one.
That is the Ford Focus, a
very light but powerful vehicle.
It comes with dual-side
airbags, power steering
and power windows,
tinted windows and your
choice of either automatic
or manual transmission.
Sounds like a good car.
How many miles to the gallon?
It is a very fuel-efficient
vehicle giving
you about 34 miles in the
city and 40 on the highway.
That is really convenient, especially
now the fuel prices are so high.
What's under the hood?
A very powerful 2.5 liter
turbocharged engine.
Trust me, this car is fast.
Now for the most difficult question.
What is the price tag
for this lovely vehicle?
Very affordable, ma'am.
You can take it out
of this lot today with
zero down payment and
no interest for the first year.
You can test drive it now and we
can sign the papers when we get back.
Great.
Let's do it.
All right, we're back
so now we're going to
take a look at some
of that vocab, especially
the one that the salesmen
used on language takeaway.
Language takeaway.
All right, so at the
beginning of this dialogue,
we hear a lot of
features that this car has.
The first one is trade-in, actually.
This is something that the man
says when he goes to the car lot.
That's right.
He says he has an old car.
He has a Ford Pinto and
he wants to trade it in.
He wants to trade in his old car.
So this is something
that you do in America
or other places when
you have a car already.
But you want a new car.
And so the car lot, the place where you can
buy the cars, they'll usually give you some
money for your old car and you can
spend that money on your new car.
That's right.
So basically, you give
them your old car plus
some extra cash and
then you can get a new car.
So that's basically what a trade-in is.
And well, as you said, we had a lot of
features on this car of the Ford Focus.
That's of all, dual-side airbags.
OK, so dual-side is pretty simple.
It means that you have them on both sides,
the left and the right dual means two.
But airbags are what's important in this
phrase, airbags do what exactly Marco.
They protect you from
hitting the front part of the car.
So maybe out of the steering
wheel, a bag will inflate if you crash.
So it will prevent you from hitting
the steering wheel and getting hurt.
It's like a big balloon and it protects
you from damaging your body.
That's right.
So it has two airbags for the
passenger and for the driver.
All right.
So after that, we also
heard about a number of
things that are power, power
steering power windows.
So what does power steering do?
Power steering are also
called assisted steering.
It allows you to turn
your car with less effort.
So maybe you've driven a car
that didn't have power steering.
And so you really
have to struggle when
you're turning the car,
especially if you're parking.
So you have to turn the wheel
and turn it, turn it, turn it to turn.
But power steering makes it more automatic.
So it's very easy to turn left or right.
That's right.
And the same thing goes for power windows.
So maybe your car doesn't
have electric windows.
So you have to do it
manually with a little lever.
It's a turn it around
and around and around.
But instead with
power windows, you just
push a button and the
window goes down or up.
That's right.
And actually as well, another feature
for the windows, we have tinted windows.
Now, these are sometimes very popular.
I don't think I've ever
had tinted windows on
my car, but tint means
something is darker.
It's protected from the sun.
So tinted sunglasses, for
example, can be very dark.
But tinted windows on a car are black.
They don't let much sunlight in.
So you don't get blinded by the sun or
so other people can't see you from outside.
Usually limousines, you will see
all limousines have tinted windows.
Politicians like to drive around
in cars with tinted windows.
That's right.
Okay.
So a lot of features.
There are a lot of vocab regarding the car.
Why don't we take a break.
Let's listen to the dialogue again
and we'll be back to talk some more.
Hi there.
I am looking for a new car.
I have this old Ford Pinto
that I would like to trade in.
I see.
You are in look this month because
all of our 2010 models are on sale.
It is a perfect time to buy a new
car since it's the end of the year.
Perfect.
I like this one.
That is the Ford Focus, a
very light but powerful vehicle.
It comes with
dual-side airbags, power
steering and power
windows, tinted windows and
your choice of either automatic
or manual transmission.
Sounds like a good car.
How many miles to the gallon?
It is a very fuel-efficient
vehicle, giving
you about 34 miles in the
city and 40 on the highway.
That is really convenient, especially
now the fuel prices are so high.
What's under the hood?
A very powerful 2.5-liter
turbocharged engine.
Trust me, this car is fast.
Now for the most difficult question.
That is the price tag
for this lovely vehicle.
Very affordable, ma'am.
You can take it out
of this lot today with
zero-down payment and
no interest for the first year.
You can test drive it now and we
can sign the papers when we get back.
Great.
Let's do it.
All right, we're back, so now let's
start again with language takeaway.
Now let's take a look at part 2.
Language takeaway.
So a very, very key
phrase that we heard in
the dialogue is automatic or
sometimes manual transmission.
So automatic transmission,
manual transmission,
is very important
when we talk about cars.
That's right, so
basically the car has a lot
of gears and with an
automatic transmission,
the car will basically
change gears by itself.
So you can, you start in
park and you go to drive
and you can go to
reverse park drive reverse.
That's right.
This controls kind of
the way the car moves,
but with a manual
transmission, this means
you have to do it by
yourself using your hand.
So we have what gears?
We have one, two, three,
four, and sometimes five.
That's right.
So that's a manual transmission.
You have to change the gears manually.
It's a lot of work.
Yeah.
Now, talking about another
feature of the car, the client
asked, well, how many miles
to the gallon does the car get?
And the salesman said that
the car is very fuel efficient.
Okay, so this is a very
important phrase right
now as gas is very
expensive in some parts
of the world and we are concerned
about the environment, right?
So a fuel efficient car is a
car that uses gas very well.
That means that I can go
very, very far on one tank of gas.
I don't need to keep
putting gas into my car.
That's right.
So usually, for example,
sports cars are not fuel efficient.
Hummers are not fuel efficient.
That's right.
So fuel efficient is
a key thing to look
for these days, but the customer also
wanted to know what's under the hood.
So this phrase under the hood is very,
very common when we're talking about cars.
That's right.
The person said, what's under the hood?
And basically what we're
saying is what is under the hood,
which is that metal cover
and the front part of the car.
So you lift that and there you
can have access to the engine.
So basically, that's the question.
What kind of an engine does this car have?
Oftentimes when your
car stops or you have a
problem like it's broken, someone like a
mechanic will say, hey, let's have a look.
Let's look under the hood.
He wants to know, let's look at the
engine so we can find the problem.
But in this case, it's not a problem.
He just wants to know
what kind of a car is this?
Is it powerful or is it not so powerful?
That's right.
That's exactly right.
So that's why we want
to know what's under
the hood and well, he goes on to
explain all the features about the engine.
But then when we talk
about the payment, how
much the car costs, the
salesman said, you know what?
It's not expensive.
And on top of that, you can drive it out
today with zero percent down payment.
Okay.
This is important.
Down payments are payments that you often
make with very, very big ticket items.
A house, a car, things like this.
So a down payment is what
you have to pay to get the
thing to begin using it,
but not all of the payment.
Right.
So it's a percentage.
So if the car is $10,000
and the man says,
there's a 0% down payment,
how much do I have to pay Mark?
Zero.
I don't pay anything today.
I pay in a month, a little bit,
and then next month, a little bit.
But if the payment is a 10% down
payment, then I have to pay $1,000 today.
That's right.
It's usually about things that have a
big price tech that are very expensive.
A house, a car, these types of things,
usually you need to give a down payment.
That means that you're
committing to buying it.
That's right.
So a lot of interesting things
going on in today's lesson.
Why don't we listen to the dialogue
again and we'll be back to talk some more.
Hi there.
I am looking for a new car.
I have this old Ford Pinto
that I would like to trade in.
I see.
You are in look this month because
all of our 2010 models are on sale.
It is a perfect time to buy a new
car since it's the end of the year.
Perfect.
I like this one.
That is the Ford Focus, a
very light but powerful vehicle.
It comes with
dual-side airbags, power
steering and power
windows, tinted windows, and
your choice of either automatic
or manual transmission.
It's like a good car.
How many miles to the gallon?
It is a very fuel-efficient
vehicle, giving
you about 34 miles in the
city and 40 on the highway.
That is really convenient, especially
now that fuel prices are so high.
What's under the hood?
A very powerful 2.5-liter
turbocharged engine.
Trust me, this car is fast.
Now for the most difficult question.
What is the price tag
for this lovely vehicle?
Very affordable, ma'am.
You can take it out
of this lot today with
zero-down payment and
no interest for the first year.
You can test drive it now and we
can sign the papers when we get back.
Great.
Let's do it.
All right, so buying a new
car can always be tricky.
What do you prefer, though, for example,
in these types of features of the car?
For me, a car must
be very fuel-efficient
because, number one,
cars are all bad for the
environment, so I want a car
that's less bad for the environment.
But also, I really like
manual transmission
because, number one, manual transmission
is more fuel-efficient than automatic.
Also, I like to have more
control when I'm driving.
I feel safer in a manual
transition car because
when you do manual, you actually
pay more attention to your driving.
You have to concentrate.
Automatic, you can think about other
things, listen to the music and touch.
So I think that that's a safety issue.
What do you look for?
I know you're really, really into cars.
Yeah, I actually prefer
manual transmissions
as well, most
importantly because of the
way that the car drives, especially a sports
car, it's definitely something for me.
It's nice to have a
manual transmission, but
also, you know, little
nice features like in
the exterior, like the rims, I like
nice rims or maybe a nice paint job.
Tinted windows, I'm not a very big fan
of tinted windows, but yeah, I don't know.
Some cars nowadays,
even for, as you said,
politicians, they even
sell them bulletproof.
That's why they have
bulletproof glass, very, very secure.
Well, for me, I don't
think I need bulletproof
glass, but a good
stereo is a good start.
That's right, yeah.
You want to have good speakers and
connect your iPod to the stereo now?
Exactly.
So a lot of great things
with cars and actually
the model that they mentioned, the Ford
Pinto is a very popular, but very bad car.
It was cheap.
It was cheap, but it wasn't very good.
And the 1970s and 80s,
this is a very common
car and it's famous for
being a small, cheap car.
That's right.
Like the Volkswagen Beetle.
Yes, exactly.
So maybe you can come
to our website, EnglishPod.
com, and you can tell us if you
have a car, what was your first car?
And did you buy a new car or a used car?
That's right.
So let us know.
And of course, if you
have any questions, we're
always there on the
website, EnglishPod.com.
And we'll see you guys there.
Bye.